http://www.isp.msu.edu/privacy-policy

HOME
About About ISP OverviewDean's RemarksISP LeadershipHistoryGlobal Focus Photo Contest Overview2020 Winners2020 JudgesContest GuidelinesInternational AwardsMake a GiftContactCenters & Units MSU's International OrganizationArea and Thematic Studies OverviewAfrican Studies CenterAsian Studies CenterCanadian Studies CenterCenter for European, Russian and Eurasian StudiesCenter for Latin American and Caribbean StudiesCenter for Gender in Global ContextMuslim Studies ProgramOffice of China ProgramsAffiliated Units and Centers OverviewAlliance for African PartnershipBHEARDGlobal Center for Food Systems InnovationGlobal IDEASGlobal Youth Advancement NetworkInternational BusinessInternational EducationInternational HealthOffice of International Health and SafetyPartnerships for Sustainable Community DevelopmentStudent & Scholar Programs OverviewAmerican Semester Program & ExchangesCommunity Volunteers for International ProgramsFulbright ProgramsHumphrey Fellowship ProgramJapan Center for Michigan UniversitiesInternational Student ClubsOffice for International Students and ScholarsOffice for Education AbroadPeace CorpsVisiting International Professional ProgramVolunteer English Tutoring ProgramMSU's Global Reach MSU's International StrategyThemesRegionsRelationships & PartnersInternational Data PortalInformation & Resources Information & Resources OverviewNewsEventsStudent FundingFaculty Funding OverviewGlobal IDEASInternational Travel Safety OverviewOffice of International Health and SafetyTravel RegistryInternships and CareerInternational Data PortalAcademics & Learning Academics and LearningLearning at MSU OverviewMajors and MinorsAmerican Semester Program & ExchangesVisiting International Professional ProgramLearning Abroad OverviewFulbright ProgramsJapan Center for Michigan UniversitiesOffice for Education AbroadPeace CorpsLanguage StudyInternational AdmissionsAlumni & Donors Alumni & Donors Overview OverviewCampus PartnersContact UsSignature Activities OverviewMSU Leadership Welcome for International FamiliesGet Involved OverviewInternational Parent ProgramsAlumni Clubs & CommunitiesAlumni Contacts, Ambassadors & VolunteersMSU ConnectMake a GiftInternational Insights Dialogue SeriesGlobal Spartans in Music
AboutAbout ISPDean's RemarksISP LeadershipHistoryGlobal Focus Photo Contest2020 Winners2020 JudgesContest GuidelinesInternational AwardsMake a GiftContactCenters & UnitsMSU's International OrganizationArea and Thematic StudiesAfrican Studies CenterAsian Studies CenterCanadian Studies CenterCenter for European, Russian and Eurasian StudiesCenter for Latin American and Caribbean StudiesCenter for Gender in Global ContextMuslim Studies ProgramOffice of China ProgramsAffiliated Units and CentersAlliance for African PartnershipBHEARDGlobal Center for Food Systems InnovationGlobal IDEASGlobal Youth Advancement NetworkInternational BusinessInternational EducationInternational HealthOffice of International Health and SafetyPartnerships for Sustainable Community DevelopmentStudent & Scholar ProgramsAmerican Semester Program & ExchangesCommunity Volunteers for International ProgramsFulbright ProgramsHumphrey Fellowship ProgramJapan Center for Michigan UniversitiesInternational Student ClubsOffice for International Students and ScholarsOffice for Education AbroadPeace CorpsVisiting International Professional ProgramVolunteer English Tutoring ProgramMSU's Global ReachMSU's International StrategyThemesRegionsRelationships & PartnersInternational Data PortalInformation & ResourcesInformation & ResourcesNewsEventsStudent FundingFaculty FundingGlobal IDEASInternational Travel SafetyOffice of International Health and SafetyTravel RegistryInternships and CareerInternational Data PortalAcademics & LearningAcademics and LearningLearning at MSUMajors and MinorsAmerican Semester Program & ExchangesVisiting International Professional ProgramLearning AbroadFulbright ProgramsJapan Center for Michigan UniversitiesOffice for Education AbroadPeace CorpsLanguage StudyInternational AdmissionsAlumni & DonorsAlumni & Donors OverviewCampus PartnersContact UsSignature ActivitiesMSU Leadership Welcome for International FamiliesGet InvolvedInternational Parent ProgramsAlumni Clubs & CommunitiesAlumni Contacts, Ambassadors & VolunteersMSU ConnectMake a GiftInternational Insights Dialogue SeriesGlobal Spartans in Music
Home
Privacy Policy
This online privacy statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this website (“Site”) collects information, the uses to which that information will be put, and the ways in which we protect information you choose to provide us.
Please note that other Michigan State University websites may adopt different privacy practices as their specific needs require.
Use of this Site is subject to all applicable state and federal laws, as well as general university policies.
INFORMATION COLLECTED
This Site collects two general types of information:
(a) information you voluntarily provide to us, which may include personal information (such as your name, address, email address, etc.), and (b) information we collect automatically when you visit this Site through cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs.
INFORMATION VOLUNTARILY PROVIDED BY YOU
This Site will only collect personal information that you knowingly and voluntarily provide by, for example, responding to surveys, completing membership forms, sending emails, etc.  It is this Site’s general practice to use personal information only for the purposes for which it was requested and any additional uses specifically stated on the Site. However, information collected through this Site may be subject to the university’s obligation to respond to subpoenas, court orders, discovery requests, and requests for public records under the Michigan Freedom of Information Act (PDF). Further, the disclosure of information collected through this Site is subject to the provisions of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
The university may also access or permit access to information collected through this Site in accordance with and subject to the limitations of the University’s Acceptable Use Policy for Information Technology Resources.
Although this Site has security measures in place to protect personal information provided to us by users, users should also take steps to protect personal information by, for example, closing all web browsers after using the Site. Information disclosed in chat rooms, news groups, forums, message boards and similar contexts may become public. Users should therefore exercise caution before disclosing personal information in such contexts.
A Note about personal information Our site does not save or maintain any personal information while you visit.
INFORMATION WE COLLECT AUTOMATICALLY
This Site collects information automatically through the use of cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs.  This information does not include any personal information.  We use this information primarily to monitor the use of this Site and to make improvements.  We may share this data with partners in order to enhance the functionality of this Site.
Cookies “Cookies” are small text files used to collect information about website activity.  No personal information is collected through our use of cookies.  This Site uses cookies for two main purposes:
(a) to carry information about your current session at this Site from one web page to the next, which also allows you to automatically login to other Michigan State University websites, and (b) to identify you on this Site on return visits.
You have the option of disabling or not accepting cookies by changing the preferences on your browser.  If you opt to disable cookies, you will still be able to use certain sections of our Site. However, you will not be able to use any parts of this Site that requires a login (e.g. accessing secured content, posting to message boards, etc).
Third Party Tracking Technology This Site uses a tracking technology called Google Analytics to obtain Site usage information such as users’ Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, Internet domain and host names, browser software, and the date and time that the Site is visited.  Data obtained through Google Analytics does not include and is not linked to any personal information.  Data from Google Analytics allows us to monitor the use of this Site, understand how users find our Site, and improve the Site’s function and content.
Site usage data collected through Google Analytics is not shared with other Google products and tools.  Our use of Google Analytics is in compliance with Google’s Terms of Service and the MSU Access to Student Information Guidelines.  Google provides more information about Google’s privacy practices and information on how to opt-out of Google Analytics tracking of your web browsing.
You may also wish to review the MSU Access to Student Information Guidelines.
This site uses Google Custom Search.
Server Logs Our web servers routinely generate logs that contain the following types of information each time the Site is used:
The date, time and length of your visit. The path taken through our Site and the browser being used. The list of files downloaded and the amount of time spent viewing video or audio files. The IP Address of the computer accessing our Site. Any errors encountered
This information is used primarily to monitor the functioning and integrity of the Site and other MSU websites.
LINKS
This Site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we do not control or claim any responsibility for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage users to read the privacy statements of each website they visit.
CHANGES TO PRIVACY STATEMENT
If we make changes to our privacy statement, we will indicate this on this page.
DISCLAIMER
Neither Michigan State University, nor any of its units, programs, employees, agents or individual trustees, shall be liable for any improper or incorrect use of information obtained through the use of this Site.
CONSENT
By using this Site you consent to the terms of this privacy statement.
QUESTIONS AND FEEDBACK
Your questions, comments and concerns are always welcome via our contact page.Website developed by AE Lansing Web Development
NASA funds international team of MSU and African institutions for global carbon research in trees outside of forests
Lansing-area teacher
brings global education
to the high school classroom
2020 Global Focus
Photo Contest:
Winners announced!
Engage, ask, persist:
